## **Professional Synopsis**

Having 10+ years of Overall experience as iOS/MacOS Application Developer.

Worked on Various Applications in iOS/MacOS in the fields of Financial Services, CRM, e-Commerce, Event Management and Health Care.

Working Knowledge in creating Command Line tools using shell script and XCode.

Hands on experience to Design and program iOS applications (including iPhone, iPad, iPod Touch) with XCode using the latest iOS SDK and Knowledgeable with Interface Builder as well as all core technologies, including UI Elements, Storyboards and Foundation Frameworks of Objective C, APNS, App store Procedure, Knowledge in Testing Application in Simulator, and Devices for fine tuning

Email: ssohailmails@gmail.com

Contact Number: +91-9791028803

Knowledge in Swift 5.9, SwiftUI, Apple Script, Shell Script, M1 Chipset Intel chipset understanding.

Knowledge in Notarization process for package files, Mac Apps, and iOS apps

Sound knowledge in frameworks like Firebase, Alamo fire, Realm, Pods, AR Kit framework

Have good interpersonal and communication skills and ability to work effectively with the team under project timelines.

Design, write and build application for the iOS platform, Collaborate with the team (developers, designers, product owners, QA) to define, design, and ship new features., Implement new product features and support existing ones, Prepare test plan, test cases and Execute/automate them., Identify and correct bottlenecks and fix bugs

# **Technical Expertise**

**Product:** XCode, Apple Scripts, Shell Scripts, Source Tree, Github,

Adobe experience Manager, Figma, Confluence, JIRA

**Operating Systems:** Mac 0S X, Windows

**Other Apps:** MS-Office, Pages, Packages

## **Work History**

Company: Atos Syntel

**Role:** Senior Consultant **Duration:** Oct 2022– Present

**Company:** Wipro Technologies

**Role:** Senior Software Engineer **Duration:** June 2018 – Oct 2022

Company: Hcl Technologies

**Role:** Senior Software Engineer **Duration:** April 2<sup>nd</sup>2015 – June 2018

**Company:** It Sculptors Business Systems **Role:** iOS Application Engineer

**Duration:** March 12<sup>th</sup>2014 – March 23<sup>rd</sup>, 2015

Company: Creative Thoughts Systech India Pvt Ltd.

Role: iOS Application Engineer

Duration: December 2012 – March 2014

## **Last Recent Project Details**

Title : Kaiser Permanente (Pharmacy)

: 1 years 3 months Duration Team Size : 10 Members

**Environment:** iOS

Client : Kaiser Permanente

The Kaiser Permanente app gives you a simple, secure way to manage your health - all in one place.

### Responsibilities:

Involved in Development of the app.

Code Review of Team management, Git Management.

Analysis, Improvement recommendation to client for any changes required.

Bug fixing, Scrum Testing.

Title : CUSA (Cisco Unified Setup Assistant)

Duration : 2 years

Team Size : 2

**Environment:** macOS App

Client : CISCO

Cisco Unified Setup Assistant (CUSA) for Mac dramatically simplifies Cisco computer setup by consolidating and automating a manual process of Managing Cisco enrolled Devices.

#### Responsibilities:

Involved in Development of the app from Scratch.

Project management and handing client directly thought 1-1 communication Analysis, Improvement recommendation to client for any changes required. Bug fixing Testing in Intel and M1 based macs

Title : On Track Health Score

Duration : 2 years Team Size : 2

**Environment**: macOS Terminal Based Application

Client : CISCO

OnTrack Health Score is a Terminal based application which runs as root in the background to collect all necessary Health information of User Cisco devices. The Apple Log feature helps to log all data from a users mac and share the information to IT team. It keeps your device on check with all Certificate information like Cisco Trusted Device information, Duo Device Health status, Encryption status

#### Responsibilities:

Involved in Development of the app from Scratch.

Project management and handing client directly thought 1-1 communication Analysis, Improvement recommendation to client for any changes required.

Bug fixing Testing in Intel and M1 based macs

Title : ISE Remediation

Duration : 6 Months

Team Size : 2

**Environment:** macOS App Client : CISCO

ISE Remediation is a mac App developed for the purpose of Fixing Cisco Security standards for Cisco provided mac. It installs all required Certificates to manage the device

### Responsibilities:

Involved in Development of the app from Scratch.

Project management and handing client directly thought 1-1 communication Analysis, Improvement recommendation to client for any changes required. Bug fixing Testing in Intel and M1 based macs

**Title**: Grundfos (Go Remote)

**Duration**: 12 Months

Team Size : 10

**Environment:** iPhone/iPad **Client** : Grundfos

Appstore Link: https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/grundfos-go-remote/id524685121?mt=8

Grundfos GO is a comprehensive platform for remote product control, product selection and product information. It offers intuitive, handheld assistance and access to Grundfos online tools, and it saves valuable time for reporting and data collection.

## Responsibilities:

Involved in Development of app.

Manage and develop new stories.

Conversation of bit data coming from pump.

Worked on Different UI elements.

### **Academic Credentials**

**Master of Computer Applications**, Vel Tech MultitechDr.RangarajanDr.Sakunthala Engineering College, Chennai.

Bachelor of Computer Applications, Vel Sri RangaSanku College of Arts and Science

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth: 29-11-1988

Address : new no 4 old no

7a mosque 2<sup>nd</sup> street

Villivakkam Chennai -600049

Languages known: English, Hindi, Tamil, Urdu and German (Beginner).

Nationality: Indian

**Strength**: Self Confidence, Team Worker &Self Motivating

**GitWebsite**: <a href="https://sohailurrahmangit.github.io/SohailRepository/MyWebsite/index.html">https://sohailurrahmangit.github.io/SohailRepository/MyWebsite/index.html</a>

**Declaration**: I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge.

**Shaik Sohail ur Rahman**